Stephen J. Gould papers M1437
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stephen Jay Gould papers
1942-2002
M1437
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
375.0 Linear feet
Gould, Stephen Jay
Access to Collection
Open for research. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biography
When five-year-old Stephen Jay Gould first marveled at the towering Tyrannosaurus skeleton in the American Museum of Natural History, he decided to spend his life studying fossils. Although few children in Queens, New York, shared his early fascination for evolution, he never considered any other career but paleontology.
Shearer, Rhonda Roland, 1954-; Evolution (Biology); Hist of Science; Natural history; Paleontology
- Series 1: Correspondence
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists primarily of incoming and outgoing letters. There are also a small number of letters removed from Gould's book collection.
  Incoming letters were received between 1963 and Gould’s death in 2002. These letters remain as originally ordered in Gould’s chronological files and are arranged alphabetically by correspondent. In cases where a substantial number of letters exist for a correspondent, or where the author or subject matter is of particular significance, the letters are foldered individually by correspondent. Letters foldered separately appear at the beginning of each alpha range and are followed by general alpha arrangement (for example, “Abrams, Susan” then “Aa-Ae”). Some date range overlap exists between subseries as original order was maintained. Incoming correspondence includes letters, postcards, and other documents sent to Gould by colleagues, editors, publishers, and fans. Letters from colleagues include discussion of collaborative projects, activities relating to professional organizations, routine correspondence regarding conferences and travel arrangements, and requests for recommendations, manuscript reviews, and article reprints. Letters from fans and laypersons include both praise and criticism of Gould's books, scholarly articles, popular science works, and involvement in the fields of evolutionary biology, paleontology, and the history of science. Also included are personal letters from colleagues, family, and friends.
  Outgoing letters date from 1974 to 2000, and are grouped in folders by month. Letters of particular note are indicated in the folder title. Letters include routine correspondence with editors, discussion of professional matters, responses to fan mail, and personal messages.
  Letters found in Gould's rare books have been separated and foldered individually. Folder titles indicate the volumes from which the letters were removed.
  Notable correspondents include Susan E. Abrams, Isaac Asimov, Edwin Barber, Jimmy Carter, Arthur C. Clarke, Bill Clinton, Hillary Clinton, Richard Dawkins, Alan Dershowitz, Joe DiMaggio, Carl Djerassi, Niles Eldredge, R. Buckminster Fuller, Martin Gardner, Bill Gates, Henry Louis Gates, Jr., Mikhail Gorbachev, Al Gore, Anthony Hallam, Grace Halsell, Edward M. Kennedy, Ernst Mayr, Sir Peter Medawar, Robert K. Merton, Ashley Montagu, Norman D. Newell, Linus Pauling, Jef Raskin, David M. Raup, Milton Rogovin, Carl Sagan, Eugenie Scott, Charles Sibley, George Gaylord Simpson, B. F. Skinner, John Maynard Smith, G. Ledyard Stebbins, Alan Ternes, Kurt Vonnegut, E. O. Wilson, and Sewall Wright.
  - Subseries: Incoming Letters, 1975-1979
    - Addicott, Warren O. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ager, D. V. (Derek Victor) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Aldrich, Michele L. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Allen, Garland E. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Appleman, Philip (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Aronson, Lester R. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Atchley, William R. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Awramik, S. M. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Abelson, Philip H.; Abler, William L.; Abrahamsen, Valerie; Affleck, Marilyn; Ahrnsbrak, William F.; Akersten, William A.; Alberch, Pere; Albritton, Claude; Aldridge, R. J.; Alexander, Richard R.; Allen, Arly; Allen, Gary L.; Allen, Richard M. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Alley, Thomas R.; Alt, David; Anderson, Paul K.; Anderson, R. S.; Apsey, Robert Patrick; Armbruster, Bruce; Arnheim, Rudolf; Arnstein, Walter L.; Arthurs, Alberta; Ausich, William I.; Steven A. Austin; Ayala, Francisco J. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Baer, A. J. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Baity, Elizabeth Chesley (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Baker, Victor R. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bambach, Richard K. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Banks, Edwin M. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Barber, Edwin (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bardach, Barbara (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Barlow, George W. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Barry, David G. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bates, Elizabeth (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Batten, Roger L. and Niles Eldredge (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bauchot, Roland (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Mullen, B. Gail (Beagle) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Behnke, James W. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Behnke, John A. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Behrensmeyer, Kay (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bell, Daniel (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bell, Michael A. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Belliveau, Marion C. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bennett, Thomas Peter (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Bennett, William (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Bennett-Mendez, Kate (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Berg, Sheila (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Berger, Edward (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Berger, Jacques (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Berggren, William A. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Berkstresser, Charles F., Jr. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Bethell, Tom (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Bishop, Martin (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Blake, Robert (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Blouw, Max (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Bolt, John R. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Bookstein, Fred L. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Borras, Catherine (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Bowler, Peter (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Bretsky, Peter W. (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Bretsky, Sara S. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Bretting, Peter (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Brewster, Beatrice (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Brower, James C. (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Brown, Thomas M. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Brown, William L., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Brownstein, Larry (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Brunauer, Patricia A. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bunge, Mario (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bunn, James (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Burkhardt, Frederick (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Burnett, Farrell (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Burns, John M. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Burstyn, Harold L. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Bagnara, Joseph T.; Bahm, Archie J.; Baker, James J.; Ball, John; Ballester, George, Jr.; Balon, Eugene K.; Baranowitz, Steven; Bardack, David; Barker, Crystal L.; Basden, Andrew; Baur, Werner H.; Bayley, S. T.; Bayliss, Catherine; Baynes, Alex; Kerr, Jane (Beale); Beaman, John H.; Beatty, John; Becker, Barbara A.; Beerbower, James R.; Beers, William H.; Bekoff, Marc; Bell, A. T. J.; Bell, Ian F. A.; Belt, Edward S. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Benford, Frank A.; Bennett, Ralph A.; Bergman, Barrie F.; Bernardi, Nelson; Bernhardt, Kim; Berry, Joyce; Berry, R. J.; Bertoni, Elisabetta; Beyer, Brian Nolan; Biedenweg, Doug; Bigwood, B. A.; Bijur. Victoria; Billings, Marland P.; Bingler, Edward C.; Birks, H. J. B.; Bjurstedt, Hilding; Black, Craig C.; Black, Simon; Blankenship, Jacob W.; Blanpied, William A.; Den Boer, James (Filed under "Boer"); Bogoch, Samuel; Bok, Derek C. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bonem, Rena M.; Bonner, J. T.; Boot, K. J.; Boss, Kenneth J.; Boucot, Arthur J.; Bowersock, G. W.; Boyce, A. J.; Boyd, F. R.; Boyer, Robert E.; Boylan, P. J.; Brace, C. Loring; Bradbury, Jack W.; Brady, Peter; Brannigan, Gus; Bravo, Ernesto; Bray, John; Briggs, Doras; Briskin, Madeleine; Brolin, Brent; Brothwell, D. R.; Brown, Edward H.; Brown, Phyllis G.; Brownlow, Arthur; Brussard, P. F.; Bryce, George W., Jr.; Buck, Peter; Bull, William B.; Burch, J. B.; Burchsted, Frederic F.; Burian, Richard M.; Burke, Richard; Burlingame, Leslie J.; Burnett, Christopher; Byrne, H. Desmond; Bywaters, Tom (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - B Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Cain, A. J. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Campbell, Norm A. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Campbell, Robert (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Caplan, Arthur (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Carey, William D. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Carson, Hampton (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Carson, Teresa (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Caster, Kenneth (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Chappell, John E., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Ciochan, Russell L. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Clark, George R., II (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Clench, William J. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Cloud, Preston (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Cobb, W. Montague (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Cohen, Irene (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Cohen, Robert S. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Cole, Mike (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Coleman, William (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Collicott, Andrew Bottan (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Coon, Carleton (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Conrad, Ernie (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Cook, James (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Crompton, A. W. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Cronin, Tom (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Crumly, Charles R. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Currie, Philip J. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Cairns, James A; Camber, Bruce Earl; Cameron, Barry; Campbell, Donald T; Campon, Rita; Cantor, Gordon; de Caprariis, Pascal; Carawan, Talmage; Carey; Thomas; Carlisle; E. Fred; Carr, W. J.; Carroll, Robert L.; Carroll, Thomas P; Carter; Joseph; Cartmill, Matt Caswell, Hal (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Cerva, Barbara; Chaisson, Eric; Chalmiers; Harry; Char, M. B. S.; Chartkoff, Joesph L.; Chase, Allan; Chastain, R. Murray; Chatterjee, Sankar; Cherfas, Jeremy; Chevalier, Peggyann; Childers, David W.; Christenson, Terry E.; Chu, Penn Richard; Churchill, Frederick (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Clark, George M.; Clark, Sarah F.; Clayton, Robert N.; Clegg, Michael T.; Clemens, W. A.; Cock, Alan; Coe, Robert; Cogan, Robert D.; Cohen, Alvin; Cohen, Hyman; Cohen, Jack; Cohen, Nathan; Cohen, Ralph; Colbert, Edwin H.; Cole, Charles J.; Cole, John R.; Cole, Ned S.; Coleman, Jules; Collins, D. H.; Collins, James P.; Colp, Ralph, Jr.; Colwell, Robert K. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Condon, Margaret (Peg); Congdon, Gordon; Connor, Edward F.; Conroy, Glenn; Cooper, Brenda; Cooper, Edwin L.; Corey, Gail Sprecht; Corliss, John O.; Corr, Michael; Corrsin, Stanley; Cota-Robles, Eugene H.; Coull, Bruce C.; Cowen, Richard; Cox, Stephen F.; Cracraft, Joel; Craig, G. Y.; Crawford, Daniel J.; Crow, James F.; Crowell, Kenneth; Cruise, James E.; Cymes, Sue (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - C Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Danielli, James (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Darling, D. Chris (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Davis, Charles C. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Davis, George M. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Dawkins, Richard (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Debus, Allen C. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Decker, Robert W. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - DeHaan, Robert L. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Delson, Eric (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - DeMott, Lawrence (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Desmond, Adrian (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Devons, Samuel (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Dickinson, Mary H. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Dillon, Robert (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Doyle, James A. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Dunne, Jack (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Dunson, William A. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Dahrendorf, Ralf; Daly, Howell V.; Dalziel, Ian W.; Davis, Bernard D.; Davis, Dwight B.; Davis, Monte; Davis, Whitney; Davitasvili, Leo; Delgado, Sonia Borges; Delsol, Michel; Demetrius, Lloyd; Deming, W. Edwards; Demsky, Kenneth; Destro, D. G.; Deyrup, Mark; Dial, Ben E.; Dickson, Pete; Dillingham, Beth; DiMento, Joseph F.; Distel, Robert J.; Dixon, Thomas (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Dobson, Mike; Dodson, Maurice; Doermann, Eleanor; Doherty, Jim; Domowitz, Janet; Doner, Chris; Donovan, Jessica; Dorit, Robert L.; Downs, Theodore; Drake, Charlotte; Dratch, Peter; Dreyer, Herbert H.; Driese, Steven G.; Drum, Ryan; Dudley, Bettina; Duffy, John; Dunathan, Harmon; Dunn, Daphne Fautin; Dunnell, Robert C.; Dutton, Alan R.; Dyer, Richard; Dym; Clive L.; Dyson-Hudson, Rada (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - D Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Edwards, Ronald (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Eldredge, Niles (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Elsasser, Walter M. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Engelhardt, H. Tristram (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Enslow, Ridley M. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Erickson, J. Mark (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Ericson, Edward L. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Estabrook, George F. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Eades, James L; Eaglesfield, Jean; Easton, William H.; Eaton, Randall; Eckelmann, F. Donald; Edel, Matt; Edmund, Gordon; Egelman, Ed; Eggles, John; Egler, Frank E; Ekblaw, Joyce Anne; Elenhard, Bill; Elkana, Yehuda; Elias, Paul; Ellenberger, C. Leroy; Elliott, Jean Marie; Ellis, Jim (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Endrody, Eva; Epps, A. C.; Epstein, Jason; Epstein, Martin; Erdahl, Emma; Ernst, W. G.; Erpino, Michael J.; Erwin, J.; Eschman, Donald F.; Evans, Francis C.; Eyde, Dick (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - E Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Fagen, Robert M. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Farago, John M. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Felberbaum, Arthur J. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Feldesman, Marc R. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Feldman, Howard R. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Feldmann, Rodney M. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Ferrell, Tom (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Fine, Paul E. M. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fishbein, Sy (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Fisher, Daniel (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Fishman, Ann (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Flanagan, Dennis (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Flanders, Peter (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Fleming, George (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Flessa, Karl W. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Foley, Erin (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Frank, H. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Freeman, William H. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Friedman, Dick (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Friedman, Kenneth (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Futuyama, Douglas J. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Faden, Robert; Falconer, D. S.; Farber, Paul L.; Farner, Donald S.; Faul, Henry; Febinger, Dennis L.; Felley, James; Fellows, Julia; Felsenstein, Joe; Fessenden, Jane; Fetonte, Donna; Fiala, Kent; Figueira, Armando J. G.; Fink, Sara; Finkle, Mark; Finn, Bernard S.; Fischer, Kurt W.; Fischer, George W.; Fitch, Walter M.; Fixx, James F. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Flaherty, Patricia; Fleagle, John G.; Fleiss, Paul M.; Florian, Al; Flory, Walter S.; Fluehr-Lobban, Carolyn; Folk, Robert L.; Fogarty, Robert S.; Foose, Richard M.; Ford, Glyn; Forman, Janet; Foster, Harry; Frankel, Vicki; Frankel, Richard; Frankenberg, Dirk; Frauenfelter, George H.; Frazier, Kendrick; Freeman, Gary; Frey, John J.; Friedman, Joel; Friel, Edward; Fritsche, Joellen M.; Frondel, Clifford; Fry, Wayne; Frye, B. E.; Frye, John C.; Fullagar, Paul D.; Fultz, Pat; Furtado, Joao S. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - F Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Galler, Lynne (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Gans, Carl (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Gardner, Howard (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Garraty, John A. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Gavan, James (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Geist, Val (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Gering, Ted (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - German, Rebecca (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Gillis, William T. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Gingerich, Philip D. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Gladstone, Doug (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Gladstone, Francis (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Gladstone, Jo (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Golden, William T. (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Goldman, Phaon (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Goldsmith, Timothy H. (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Goldway, David (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Gooch, James L. (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Goodfriend, Glenn A. (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Goodman, William B. (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Gordon, Robert B. (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Gould, Leonard (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Graham, James (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Grant, Verne (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Grant, Richard E. (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Graubard, Stephen R. (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Grene, Marjorie (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Grimwade, A. M. (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Gullette, Margaret L. M. (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Gaemers, Pieter; Gaensle, Eric; Gamser, Matthew; Gardner, William E.; Garland, James A.; Garrison, David N.; Gaspari, George D.; Gavan, James A.; Gay, Lynne; Gazzaniga, Michael S.; Geiser, Doris R.; Gellert, Abby Plitt; Gerald, Rex E.; Gerety, Kathleen; German, Rebecca; Gerratt, Malcolm; Ghiselin, Michael; Gibbon, Samuel Y., Jr.; Gibbs, Allan; Gieryn, Thomas F.; Gifford, Prosser; Gilbert, Edward; Giles, Norman; Gill, Frank B.; Gillette, Howard F.; Gillette, Richard; Gilinsky, Norman L.; Gillis, William T. (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Glucksberg, Sam; Godfrey, Laurie; Goitein, Elon; Gold, Bert; Goldberg, Hannah; Godlberg, Lazer; Goldman, Martin; Goldsen, Rose K.; Goldsmith, Naomi F.; Goldstone, Jack A.; Goodell, Rae; Gonsalves, Neil; Goodhart, C. B.; Goodwin, Brian; Goreau, Nora I.; Gorman, James M.; Gosliner, Terrence M.; Gottlieb, Gilbert; Gottlieb, Leslie; Goudsmit, Esther; Gould, Josiah B.; Gould, Lucinda; Gould, Margaret C.; Gould, Stephen Jay (Outgoing); Goulden, Clyde E.; Graham, Jonathan; Graham, Loren; Greaves, W. S.; Greenberg, Gary; Greene, Harry W.; Greene, Murray; Greenwood, J. J. D.; Gregory, Joseph T.; Gregory, Murray R.; Greiner Gertrude; Greiner, Roy; Greller, Andrew W.; Gruber, Jacob W.; Gruffydd, LL. D.; Gruson, Edward S. (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - G Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Hallam, Anthony (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Hallers-Tjabbes, Cato ten (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Halsell, Grace (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Hapgood, Fred (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Harnad, Stevan R. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Harper, Charles (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Harvey, Paul H. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Harward, Donald W. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Haslun, Robert A. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Hecht, Max K. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Hedgpeth, Joel W. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Henderson, Margaret (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Heron, Duncan (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Hershler, Robert (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Holton, Gerald (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Horvitz, Robert J. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Huber, Ivan (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Hull, David L. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Haberman, M. A.; Hagy, George W.; Hahn, Martin E.; Hahn, Roger; Hairston, Nelson G., Jr.; Hakerem, Gad; Hall, Elizabeth; Hall, Diana Long; Hall, W. G.; Halvorson, Harlyn O.; Hammond, Allen L.; Hanley, John H.; Hanor, Jeffrey S.; Hansen, Bert; Hansen, Bill; Havens, Leston L.; Hay, William W.; Hayami, Itaru; Hayamz, J.; Hays, Warren; Hazel, Joe; Healey, Chris; Heatwole, Harold; Harrington, William F.; Harrow, Harriett; Hartl, Daniel L.; Hartman, Willard D. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Hefta, Gunder; Held, Lewis I., Jr.; Helfand, Michael S.; Heller, Joseph; Helms, Carl W.; Heltne, Paul G.; Henderson, Harry; Hickey, Donal; Hickman, James C.; Hickman, Carole; Hiebert, Erwin N.; Hildebrandt, Katherine; Hill, Robert B.; Hirsch, Carol; Hoagland, Elaine; Hoar, George A.; Hockett, Chas F.; Hodosh, Ralph J.; Holderness, Jan; Holmes, Robert; Holt, A. B.; Hoover, Peter R.; Hopson, James A.; Horder, T. J.; Howard, Joan E.; Howden, Henry F.; Howden, Anne T.; Howe, Bob; Howe, Henry F.; Hsu, Lynne; Hubbard, Ruth; Hubbell, Stephen P.; Hubley, Faith; Hudson, John; Hughes, Chris P.; Hughes, Kathly; Humes, Arthur G.; Hunt, Joseph M.; Hunt, Richard M.; Hurst, John M. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - H Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Iltis, Hugh H. (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Imbrie, Johns (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Immergut, Edmund H. (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Ingram, Joe (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Isard, Walter (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Isay, Jane (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Ingram, Roy L.; Issac, Ephraim (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - I Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Janson, Joseph B., II (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Jefferies, R. P. S. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Jenkins, Farish A., Jr. (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Jerison, Harry J. (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Johnson, Andrew L. (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Johnson, Ralph G. (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Johnson, Ralph M. (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Johnson, Verna C. (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Johnson, Richard F. (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Jablonski, David; Jackson, Dennis; Jackson, Jane; Jacoby, Tamar; James, Frances C.; Jameson, Stephen, C.; Jaroff, Leon; Jellinek, Roger; Jenkins, D. Graham; Jenkins, Stephen H.; Johnson, J. G.; Johnson, John I.; Johnson, Robert Karl; Jolicouer, Pierre; Jolivet, P; Jones, Anna; Jones, Carol; Jones, J. S.; Jones, Richard E.; Jones, Roger R.; Jordan, Wiliam H., Jr.; Jordanova, Ludmilla; Jurkiewicz, M. J. (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - J Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Kaesler, Roger L. (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Kaplan, Robert H. (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Kardong, Kenneth V. (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Kasinsky, Harold (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Kauffman, Erle G. (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Kelly, Allan O. (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Kesten, Joanne L. (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Kier, Porter M. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - King, Charles E. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Kitts, David B. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Knoll, Andrew H. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Kohlberger, William (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Kokshaysky, Nikolai V. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Kriz, Jiri (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Kurten, Bjorn (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Kurtz, Paul (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Kalikow, Theo; Kalish MacGuineas, Carol; Kamen, Leo; Kamen-Kaye, Maurice; Kamil, Alan C.; Kaniss, Phyllis; Karten, Harvey J.; Katz, Matthew M.; Kaufman, Brian; Kaufmann, William; Kay, Richard F.; Keenan, Edward L.; Keller, Allen S.; Kellogg, Davida E.; Kelsey, Karen; Kennedy, Manert H.; Kennedy, V. S.; Kennedy, W. J.; Kennett, James P.; Kent, Dennis V.; Kenward, Michael; Keppel, John; Kerr, Michael E.; Keyes, Ralph; Ketz, Louise B.; Kidwell, J. F. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Kersey, Dave; Kilson, Marion; Kimball, Dorothy F.; Kjellesvig-Waering, Erik N.; Klapper, Gilbert; Klass, Perri; Klein, Lowell; Klevezal, G. A.; Klotz, Irving M.; Klovan, J. E.; Kluge, A. G.; Koenig, Rhoda; Kohanski, Carole; Kohn, David; Kolata, Gina Bari; Kornberg, Warren; Kottler, Malcom; Kramer, Clyde Y.; Kricher, John C.; Krieger, Robert E.; Kronenberg, Lee H.; Kruskal, William; Kuehn, David P.; Kuhry, B.; Kunkler, Julie; Kyburg, Henry E., Jr.
    - K Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Land, Lynton S. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Lande, Russell (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Landman, Neil (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Lane, Ann J. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Laporte, Leo F. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Laub, Richard S. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Leahy, Richard G. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Lein, M. Ross (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Leitenberg, Milton (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Leith, Brian H. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Leopold, Estella (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Lesk Michael (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Leutenegger, Walter (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Levi, Herbert W. (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Levin, Simon A. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Levinsohn, June (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Levinton, Jeffrey S. (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Levitas, Mitchel (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Lewis, Ralph W. (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Lifton, Robert Jay (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Lindzey, Gardner (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Linsley, Robert M. (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Lipson, Eden (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Livingston, Katherine (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Lovtrup, Soren (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - LaFarge, Ann; Laibman, David; Lal, D.; Lalvani, Haresh; Land, Dick; Landan, Rachel; Langham, Ian; Larson, Susan G.; Lateiner (Dibble), Louise; Laudan, Rachel; Lauder, George V.; Laws, Joan; Lazarus, Dave; Leake, Luther; Leamy, Larry; Lecanuet, Jean; Lee, Patrick C.; Lees, Susan H.; Lehmann, U.; Levinton, Jeffrey S.; LeResche, Linda; Levi-Setti, R.; Lewis, Giles; Lewin, Roger (Box 6, Folder 38)